# Leonardo Paixão

Aracaju, Sergipe, Brazil



leonardorpaixao@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/leonardo-paixao

## **Summary**

Graduated in Information Systems, with significant banking experience, helping to build a bank intitution from nothing, I've been working professionally with Android development for almost 5 years, and more than 2 as a tech leader. With easy communication, I consider myself a curious person who does his best to help grow everyone close to me.

## **Experience**



### **Technical Lead - Remote**

Stone

Apr 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Responsibilities

In this challenge I'm in charge of a mutiplatform team (Android, IOS and WEB), who develop the following features:

- Receivables: feature where the user can track receipts for all their sales.
- Bank domicile: feature where the user can select where receive the values of their sales.

As a experienced developer, I'm working to help others developers to reach out a new level in their careers. Producing internal content, making 1:1 conversations.

Impacts

We are reducing operating cost of the company, delivering better experience to use, avoiding the customer direct contact. Until now, we have 50% less contacts about the subject "change account domicile" in the last 9 months.

## Android Tech Lead - Remote

Stone

Jul 2021 - Jun 2022 (1 year)

Responsibilities

As a team leader, I was responsible for a team of 6 developers, following their personal and professional development. In addition, I made the bridge between developers and demands of product team, stipulating deadlines, creating and validanting tasks, correcting bugs, and developing when needed. Futhermore, participated of the release process of new versions of Android app on Google Play Store.

In charge of following features

- Prepay credit card emission
- Account registration
- KYC Identity checks
- Salary portability
- Profile Information

- Payment invoices creation and payment.
- Prepay feature that antecipate to our customers values from their sells.
- Impact
- Released a new refactored version of one of biggest profitable product of the company, Prepay.
- Released the prepaid card product.
- Helped to build first BFF for the prepay card product.

## Android Developer - Remote

#### Stone

Jul 2019 - Jul 2021 (2 years 1 month)

Conta Stone is a mobile application available in PlayStore who grant access to a digital banking account.

- Responsibilities
- Maintain the application, fix bugs, implement new features, update layouts.
- Participate actively to the improvement process, giving feedback to our product team and my teammates.
- Impact

Collaborate with multiple teams to launch a banking app from scratch.

Awards

Grade "A" on the annual performance review for two years.

- · Used technologies
- Consume API Rest with MVVM Architecture.
- Async requests with Retrofit, Json, Kotlin serialization, RxJava, RxKotlin, Coroutines | Flow
- UI development with Jetpack Compose and traditionalway.
- Scalable multi module project
- Dependency Injection with Kodein, Koin and Hilt
- Firebase database

## Banking Technician - On-site

#### Banese

Nov 2015 - Jun 2019 (3 years 8 months)

I worked with the Account Control, Payments and Court Orders Area - ACOMP.

Responsibilities

Prepare official responses to incoming legal demands in addition to monitoring irregularities in the accounting of legal accounts.

- Impact
- Participated actively in the improvement of processs, corrections and validations of the systems that met the legal demands sent by BACEN and the State judicial deposit management system.

- Helped the institution to Identify and recover potential losses contained for almost 4 years in ledger accounts.



## Android Developer - On-site

### CalangosTaxi

Jul 2018 - May 2019 (11 months)

Calangos Taxi was a personal project and also my undergraduate thesis, it was a mobile application available in Google Play Store that managed intercity rides. There were two apps, one for the passenger and another for the taxi driver.

Used technologies:

Android Studio, Bitbucket, Firebase LiveData, Async tasks and Firebase Authentication.

### **Education**



## Universidade Federal de Sergipe

Bachelor's Degree, Information Systems 2012 - 2018

### **Licenses & Certifications**



in Leadership without Formal Authority - LinkedIn

### **Skills**

Kotlin • Android • Communication • Accounting • GitHub • Java • Leadership • English